原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     折千纸鹤的小熊    米帅家的薇薇安
翻译     普利星布里狗     肉塔
翻译     徐棒棒    木浅
翻译     高庭玫瑰   PiPi
鸣谢     后期：小海    校对：不高兴童鞋    监制：渔夫
校对     木浅
校对     普利星布里狗
校对     何何超人丶拼命三郎丶心疼自己
校对     冰卡
时间轴    姜姜不打胰岛     浪影书构狐狸河
时间轴    全身纹大葱
WEB版    时间轴   何何超人丶拼命三郎丶心疼自己
后期     填坑的渔夫不纹身
特效     何何超人丶拼命三郎丶心疼自己
精校     何何超人丶拼命三郎丶心疼自己
总监     何何超人丶拼命三郎丶心疼自己
最新海外影视剧下载
人人词典
使用人人词典查词学习，美剧原声朗读与例句场景
Prison Break
微信扫描
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break...
那些攻击越来越近了
The strikes are getting closer.
我们应该还有一天
We got a day,
顶多两天时间离开这鬼地方
maybe two, tops, to get out of this hole.
非常时期  非常手段
Desperate times, desperate measures.
迈克尔想联系我们
Michael's reaching out to us.
我们得找人帮忙  一个叫希巴的女人
We got to get help. A woman named Sheba.
你弟弟喜欢说谜语  是不是
Your brother speaks in riddles, does he?
ISIL的人  我们的车会被拦下来
ISIL. We're gonna get stopped.
不如我们忘记彼此的存在
Why don't we forget each other ever existed.
美人可不是那么轻易就被忘记的
Beauty's not so easily forgotten.
上头肯定有人吧  拜格威尔
Friends in high places, Bagwell.
我可以给你配备一个行动自如的义肢
I can equip you with a fully articulate prosthetic.
-谁在背后指使  -没人
- Who's behind this? - ‭Nobody.
这就是卡尼尔·乌提斯
This is Kaniel Outis.
卡尼尔·乌提斯
系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被中情局通缉
卡尼尔·乌提斯
系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被联调局通缉
好吧  但你我都知道
Okay, but you and I both know
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德是谁
who Michael Scofield was.
我们触发了一些事
We've awoken something,
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
something people are trying to hide about Michael.
雅各布
Jacob?
这就是博弈论  你会遇见别人
That's game theory. You meet people.
把他们带入自己的生活
You bring them into your life
直到
until the moment
需要为自己而利用这些关系的那一刻
you need to manipulate the relationship to your advantage.
你答应了帮他  那怎么帮
You agreed to help him... how?
只要我能想办法让全城停电
If I could arrange a blackout.
他认识的一个人就能帮他逃出来
He knew someone who could get him out.
有人找到了我的父亲
Someone found my father.
那意味着越狱开始了
It means the escape is on.
同时  ISIL的武装分子决心
ISIL forces are also bent on
要解救其领导人阿布·拉马尔
freeing their leader Abu Ramal,
他以其极端的观点和做法而闻名
known for his extreme views and practices.
你为我们安排好出去的路了吗
是的  就在明晚
也门
奥杰吉亚监狱
看  "泡泡糖侠"又给我们送东西了
他说是"泡泡糖侠"派他来的
He says Bubble Gum Man sent him.
是在监狱里的人  他也没见过
Someone in the prison he hasn't met,
不过他用泡泡糖作为给他的差遣费
but gives him gum in exchange for errands.
他说他很害怕
He says he's frightened.
告诉他没事的
Tell him it's all right.
问他收不收嘀嗒糖
Ask him if he does Tic Tacs.
如果他继续送信
He can have the whole lot
他就能拿到一大堆
if he keeps the messages coming.
谢谢你  "嘀嗒糖侠"
Thank you, Tic Tac Man.
嘀嗒  嘀嗒  嘀嗒
Tic Tac, Tic Tac, Tic Tacs.
这是《古兰经》中的一段文字
It's a passage from the Suras.
"然后尤瑟夫对囚犯说
"And Yusef said to the prisoner:
"求你在主面前想起我"
'Remember me in the presence of your lord.'
"但是撒旦使他忘记了这件事"
"But Satan made him forget,"
"于是尤瑟夫在监狱里被关了很多年"
"And Yusef stayed in prison for several years."
这种笔迹很古怪
The calligraphy is unusual,
间隔和组成的形状
the spacing, the way it's shaped,
像是车轮上的辐条
like, like spokes on a wheel.
就像萨那的中心
Like the center of Sana'a.
你觉得他弟弟送来了一幅地图吗
You think his brother sent us a map?
这里有一个红点
There's a red dot
表明他所在的地方
dotting the "I",
不管这是哪里
and whatever this is here.
他想告诉我们一个位置
He's trying to give us a location.
什么的位置
A location for what?
我唯一能想到的
The only thing I can think of
就是当他今晚越狱之时
is where we're supposed to meet him
期望和我们会合的地方
when the escape goes down tonight.
现在你弟弟的事我不掺和了
Your brother is your business now.
今晚我得和家人赶在机场关闭前
I have to get my family on a flight tonight
一起上飞机
before the airport shuts down.
等等
Hold up.
我们也需要机票  我们三个人
We need tickets, too, three of them.
我  迈克尔  钞票哥
One for me, one for Michael, one for C.
如果我还能搞到机票  也会给这些孩子
If I'm getting anybody any tickets it's these kids,
不会给你唯利是图的弟弟
not your mercenary brother.
没有钱  你要怎么买到那些机票
And how are you going to do that without any money?
你要拿这些孩子的自由威胁我  是吗
You're holding these kids' freedom over my head; is that it?
希巴  只要你帮我买到那些机票
Sheba, you get me those plane tickets,
我会支付所有孩子的机票费用
and I'll pay for every single one of these kids
让他们逃出这个国家
to get out of this country.
直觉告诉我  不管怎样你都会这么做
Something tells me that's what you want to do anyhow.
说话可要小心哦
Careful.
你这是在"责备"我良心未泯
You're accusing me of having a heart.
走开  都走开
Out of my way. Get out of my way.
怎么  你想走吗
What, you want to go?
冷静点
Keep it together.
你必须万事俱备了我才能冷静
You got to have it together to keep it together.
在经历了这么长时间的炮击后
One of those hits us now,
终于有一颗炮弹击中我们这了  我发誓...
after all this time, I swear to God... ‭
九个小时
Nine hours.
我们九个小时后就能离开  你明白吗
Nine hours till we get out, you understand?
就在凌晨1点
It's 1:00 A.M.
我们熬过今天  就能逃出监狱了
We get through today and we're on the bricks.
那又怎样
And then what?
那是四年前了
It was four years ago.
我们的全部计划  护照  还有那家店
All of our plans, the passports, the shop,
现在可能全都埋在废墟下了
everything is probably under rubble by now.
我找到人来处理这件事了
I got someone on it.
什么  就那个捡你纸飞机的孩子吗
What, the kid you throw planes to?
不是
No.
我说的是这世界上我唯一信任的人
I'm talking about the only person I trust in the world
就和我信任你一样
as much as I trust you.
就是这里了  地图上的那个点
So, this is it, the spot on the map.
原主人说他四年前
The owner says he sold the auto shop
把这家汽修店卖给了一个美国人
to an American four years ago
那之后就没见过他了
and hasn't seen him since.
你知道那个美国人是迈克尔  对吧
You know that American was Michael, right?
问题是他用这个地方做什么呢
Question is what was he using this place for.
谋划他的越狱
Planning his escape.
看起来他原定的撤退点
It looks like his original exfil point
是在北面边界
was at the northern border.
现在可没法那么做了
Won't be doing that now.
那已是ISIL恐怖组织的地盘了
It's ISIL territory.
模板  护照照片
Mock-ups, passport photos,
伪装
disguises.
不过看起来他打算不只把自己弄出来
But it looks like he just wasn't planning on getting himself out.
他还要把阿布·拉马尔弄出来
He was getting Abu Ramal out.
这家伙是一切文明发展的敌人  老林
This guy's the enemy of everything that's civilized, Linc.
这就回到我真正的问题上了
That brings me to my real question.
我们到底是在帮谁越狱
Who in the hell are we breaking out?
是迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Is it Michael Scofield
还是卡尼尔·乌提斯
or Kaniel Outis?
把异教徒围起来
把离经叛道者也围起来
到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
拉马尔的人要执行伊斯兰教教法
Ramal's men are gonna institute Sharia law.
而那个混蛋却打算作壁上观
And that son of a bitch himself is gonna enjoy the show.
我们只要低着头  熬过这关
We just have to keep our heads down and get through this
今晚就能逃出去了
so we can get out tonight.
把他们单独分离出来
Separate them.
那些玷污了我们土地的同性恋  抓住他们
他们必须为其罪行受罚
不  不  别让他们抓我走
No. No, don't let them take me!
不
No! ‭
这人是离经叛道者吗
-对不起  -不
- Sorry. - ‭No!
当一个男人
骑到另一个男人身上
真主的王权必然动摇
拉马尔
Ramal!
狗杂种  放了他
You bastard! Just let him go.
拉马尔
Ramal!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-别管这事  -不行
- Stay out of this. - ‭No.
今晚就要越狱
The escape is tonight.
如果你想出去  你需要我  你还需要他
If you want to get out, you need me and you need him.
说重点
Get to the point.
放了他  拉马尔
Let him go, Ramal.
那我来
Then I'll do it.
别碰他
Do not touch him.
一边去  小子
Get back, dog!
这所监狱里严禁杀人  明白了吗
There will be no killing in this prison.... Understand?
他以前就试着联系过她
He's tried to contact her before.
唯一不同的是这次他成功了
Only difference is he succeeded this time.
走了那个男孩这步棋  高明
It's smart... going through the boy.
问一个问题
Ask a question?
我们为什么不跟这个女人来硬的呢
Why are we pulling our punches with this woman?
几天前姐被派去她家
I got sent to her house a couple of days ago,
才准备大开杀戒  却在姐杀她前
started spilling blood, but I'm just supposed to stop
给姐喊停了
before I start spilling hers.
这是怎么回事
How's that work?
你会习惯波塞冬的游戏规则的
You'll get used to Poseidon's game.
这一切就是一盘棋
It's all chess.
就是一场秀
It's a performance.
一场设计好  让乌提斯联系她的表演
A performance designed to make Outis reach out to her.
现在我们要做的就是窃听
Now all we got to do is listen in,
弄清他葫芦里到底卖的什么药
find out what his plans are.
而且她还没有察觉
And she doesn't know it.
她就是能帮我们顺藤摸瓜的人
She's the one that's going to lead us to him.
他们说我上午可以出院了
They said I can go in the morning.
你的股动脉被切断了
Your femoral artery was severed.
这可不是通常那种站起来就能没事走人的伤
That's not something you usually just get up and walk away from.
他们跟我说可以了
Hey, they gave me the okay.
他们才是主治医生  而不是你
They're the doctors on this one, not you.
而且我在这都快疯了  所以我要出院
And I'm going full mental in here, so I'm gonna go.
好吧  这样如何
Okay. How about this?
等你真能出院时
When you are discharged,
我们去你父母的湖畔小屋怎么样
why don't we go up to your parents' lake house?
我和麦克一起接上你就出发
I'll just pick you up with Mike and we'll go.
你不想在家里待着  对不对
You don't want to be in the house, do you?
有人闯进你家
Somebody comes into your house
朝你丈夫开枪  而且仍然逍遥法外
and shoots up your husband and they're still out there.
不想
No.
怎么了
‭What?
没什么  就是你下定决心的时候
No, it's just something you do with your nose
会动鼻子
when you're determined.
-会动鼻子吗  -很难察觉
- With my nose? - ‭It's subtle.
-真的很难察觉  -最好如此
- I mean, it's really subtle. - Better be.
你的脸真精致
The face is amazing.
我是说
I mean,
最细微的细节  哪怕失之毫厘
the tiniest detail, less than a millimeter,
也会差之千里
differentiates everything.
同一种表情在一个人的脸上可以是
An emotion on one person can be...
非常心神不安的
so troubled
而在另一个人脸上
and on another...
却如此美丽动人
...so beautiful.
你不是在动什么坏主意吧  奈斯先生
You're not trying to get somewhere, are you, Mr. Ness?
事实上
Yes, actually,
还真是
I am.
手机已锁
手机已解锁
你好啊
Hello there.
我们是一伙的  莎拉
I come as a compatriot, Sara.
你给我闪开  不然我就喊了
Get out of my way or I'll scream.
我最不希望那样了
Last thing I want.
不妨先听听我说的
For your information,
我知道卡尼尔·乌提斯的事
I know about Kaniel Outis.
说说你都知道什么
Tell me what you know.
我从福克斯河监狱刑满释放那天
The day I hit the bricks from Fox River,
有个叫乌提斯的人
someone named Outis,
大发善心
out of the goodness of their soul,
主动捐给我这个新式义肢
unsolicited, pays for this modern prosthesis.
你说什么
What's that?
值一百万美元吗
A million bucks?
为什么会有人对我这种卑鄙小人倾囊相助呢
Why would anyone come out of a pocket for a wretch like me,
一分都不可能  更别说一百万了
a penny, much less a million bucks?
如果你是来找我要答案的话  我无可奉告
Yeah, if you're coming to me for answers, I don't have any.
我找过答案了  莎拉医生
Oh, I went looking for answers, Doc Sara.
我在网上查询了乌提斯这个人
I looked up Outis on the Interwebs.
结果出现了你已故前夫的脸
Whose face comes up but your dead ex-husband's,
看着生龙活虎着呢
looking very much alive.
拉撒路死而复生了
Lazarus arisen from the dead.
[拉撒路  在圣经约翰福音中因病而死
最后被耶稣复活]
他是不是想拉我们去做什么事
He's drawing us into something, isn't he?
他是不是想要什么东西
He wants something, doesn't he?
你要是再接近我或是我的家人  我就杀了你
Come near me or my family again, I will kill you.
我们最好站在同一战线上  莎拉
Better to have me on your side, Sara.
我们可以一起解决的
We can figure this out together.
我们都听说了外面的战争
We have all heard the war outside.
但是就算只在高墙之内
But even if it is just within these walls,
这个国家的法律仍然健在
the law of the land is still in place.
真主之法必然取代这腐朽之国的法律
The law of God supersedes the law of this corrupt land.
我们不会再退化回动物
We will not be reduced to animals.
你还信任他  真是不可思议
Amazing you still trust him.
他会利用你越狱  然后就甩了你
He will use you for the escape and he will leave you.
没有人要越狱
No one's escaping.
你是什么人
Who are you?
这个监狱里最了解你朋友的人
A man who knows your friend there more than anyone in this prison.
我跟他一起关禁闭好多年
I was in solitary with him for years.
我也是
Yeah, so was I.
但你没被关过他对面的禁闭室
But not in the cell across from him.
他跟我说过越狱的事情
He told me about the escape.
-我们必须联手  -不行
- We have to work together. - ‭No.
他曾试图说服我跟他一起越狱
Tried to convince me to go with him,
只有我们两个人
just the two of us.
但是我拒绝了他
But I told him no.
我是不会离开我兄弟的
I would not leave my brother.
我体内仍流淌着军人的血
That is the Army in me,
也流淌着基督徒的血
the Christian in me.
他是个机会主义者
He is an opportunist.
他会利用任何他所需要的人
He will use whoever he needs.
我知道他已跟你说过越狱的事了
He has told you something about the escape. I know he has.
你跟他在一个牢房里  你
You were in the cell with him. You.
你告诉我  我就能帮你
You tell me, so I can help you,
赶在他利用你把那个大魔头弄出监狱
before he uses you to get that devil out
却把我们留在这里等死之前
and we are all left here to die.
我们需要护照  奥玛  你能帮我们吗
We need passports, Omar. You think you can help us?
等等  我们能信得过这家伙吗
Hold on. We're gonna trust this guy?
他可是偷我护照在先的人
He's the one who stole my passport in the first place.
那可是诚信交易  朋友
It was honest bargaining, friend.
我什么都没得到
I took nothing.
再说  你的护照早没了
Besides, your passport is long gone,
我估计现在已经远在天边了
somewhere far overseas by now, I bet.
如果你想  我可以让办假证的再给你弄个
If you want, um, I can have the forgers make you another.
让你制作我自己的假护照吗
My own fake passport coming from you?
你还有别的选择吗
You have another option?
快决定  我要离开这座城市了
Quick. I'm leaving the city.
这里已经没有地方是安全的了
Nowhere is safe anymore.
我需要两个护照  一个给我的
I need two passports. One for me,
一个给我弟弟的  迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
one for my brother, Michael Scofield.
每个护照预付一千美元
$1,000 U.S. each, deposit.
取货的时候每个再付一千美元
$1,000 U.S. when you pick them up.
钞票哥
C?
如果你敢耍我  我就杀了你
You screw with me and I'll kill you.
如果我耍你  我才不会留下等你来杀
I screw you, I won't be around for you to kill me.
今晚十一点  希巴
11 tonight, Sheba.
护照会准备好的
Passports will be ready.
那我们就得分头行动了
That means we're gonna have to split up.
你们俩去拿护照
You two get the passports,
我和这位朋友一起去发电厂
and I'll go with our friend here to the power plant
搞定停电熄灯的活儿
and kill the lights.
然后我们救迈克尔出来
And we get Michael out.
美国国务院的一位发言人称
A U.S. State Department spokesperson said
也门首都日趋沦陷
the capital of Yemen grows ever closer to collapse
萨那落入ISIL激进分子手中
and it's only a matter of time
只是时间问题罢了
until Sana'a's fallen to the hands of ISIL radicals,
预计最快明天就会彻底沦陷
with the total collapse coming as soon as tomorrow.
捷普数码店
营业中
捷 普 数 码 店
要买智能手机吗
Looking for a smartphone?
对  你...
Yeah. You, um...
你也能修手机  对吗
you fix phones, too, right?
对
Yeah.
我觉得有人黑了我的手机
I think somebody hacked my cell.
有可能帮我找出是谁干的吗
Is there any chance you can help me figure out who?
这院子里并不安全
只给十分钟吃饭时间
如果想吃饭  现在赶紧
我才不要为了让你们填饱肚子而死在这里
那个基督徒说  你对他说过你会带上他
That Christian guy said you told him you'd just take him.
不带其他人
No one else.
他是骗子  你最好别跟他扯上任何关系
He's a liar. You don't want anything to do with him.
我可说不准  基督徒  军人
I don't know. Christian, Army.
-我觉得挺靠谱  -那他有没有告诉你
- Seems pretty upfront to me. -Did he happen to tell you
他和他兄弟在他们的安检哨卡
about some of the arrests he and his brother made
-抓的那些人呢  -没  只顾着说你了
- at their security checkpoint?  - No, focused on you.
他们专抓一种人  女人
They had a specialty: women.
尸段遍布也门
Body parts strewn around Yemen.
这就是他们被关进来的原因
That's why they're here.
戴着十字架是一回事
Wearing a cross is one thing.
-以此为生就是另一回事了  -好吧  行了
- Living by it is another. - All right, okay, sure.
只要你能让我相信
Just promise me I can trust you,
你能保证我们今晚仍会行动就行
that we're still doing this tonight.
我们一起合作这么多年
All these years we've been working together,
你一直都能信任我
you've been able to trust me the whole time.
过去四年都被关在洞里  在黑暗中生活
Last four years in the hole, sitting in the dark,
甚至连个人声都听不到  我可说不准
I couldn't even hear a voice. I don't know.
说不定有什么变数或者...
Maybe something's changed or...
没有变数
Nothing's changed.
波塞冬把我们安排到这里去救拉马尔
Poseidon put us in here to get Ramal out,
但他又抛弃了我们
but then he abandoned us.
拉马尔是波塞冬的人  不是我们的
Ramal is Poseidon's guy, not ours.
-他是个禽兽  -你最好小心说话
- He's an animal. - I suggest you watch your mouth.
他们有人懂英语
Some of these guys speak English.
我们为什么还要把他弄出去
Why are we still getting him out?
我们只是跟他说要救他出去
We're telling him we're getting him out.
两者是有区别的
There's a difference.
我们必须装作跟他一伙  直到不需要他为止
We got to act like we're on his side until the moment we're not.
但万一你也是装作跟我一伙
But what if you're acting like you're on my side
直到不需要我为止呢
till the moment you're not?
你太多心了
You are getting paranoid.
换做把你关四年禁闭  你也会这样
Yeah, well, four years in the box is gonna do that to you.
我不会抛下你的
I'm not leaving you behind.
-你是我的得力干将  -这我可不确定
- You're my whip hand. - I don't know that.
我怎么确信我是你的得力干将呢
How do I know I'm your whip hand?
-之后你会明白的  -我现在就要明白
- You'll understand later. - I want to understand now.
好吗
Okay?
把你的手放开
Get your hands off me.
现在就给我答案  我是认真的
Answers, now. I'm serious.
好吧
Okay.
我叫你别碰我
I said don't touch me!
好吧
Okay.
好吧  这才像话
Okay, that's fair.
你非得这样  对吧
You want any of this?
你还想被关到洞里去吗
You want the hole again, huh?
不  我们没事
No, we're good.
不
No.
我们没事
We're good.
我们没事才怪
We're far from good.
等到明天  我们就不用再担心他了
By tomorrow, we won't have to worry about him.
萨那
伪造者之区
把头低下
Keep your head down.
不要和任何人对视
Don't make eye contact with anybody.
到处都有ISIL恐怖组织的支持者
A lot of ISIL sympathizers everywhere.
我们拿了护照就离开
We get our passports, we're out of here.
明白吗
Understand?
打算离开吗
Planning on leaving?
正当光荣革命即将开始之际
Right when the glorious revolution is beginning.
我不是来讨论政治的  只是拿护照
I'm not here for political discussion, just passports.
先交钱
Money first.
先看护照
Passports first.
护照是空白的
They're empty.
希巴
Sheba! ‭
抱歉我打了你  我可以解释
I'm sorry I hit you. I can explain.
你能解释得了为何你会让那人杀了我吗
Can you explain why you were going to let that man kill me?
我不会让他杀了你的
I wouldn't have let him kill you.
看来你和ISIL的老大确实是好基友
You sure seem to be chums with the head of ISIL, friend.
没想到你也会加入我们的谈话了  雅
Didn't know you participated in these conversations, Ja.
我只谈论有意思的话题
Only when they're interesting.
不过通常都没意思
And they're usually not.
随你信不信
There are people in my government,
我政府里有人因为
believe it or not, who want that man out
他们自己复杂的外交政策而要救那人出狱
for their own convoluted foreign policy over here.
这就是我和维普被派来做的差事
That's the job Whip and I were sent here to do.
但因为某些原因  我们被抛弃了
But for some reason, we were betrayed.
也就是说这次越狱没有拉马尔的份了
Which means we're getting out without Ramal.
你们每个人都是计划中重要的一环
And every one of you is crucial to that plan.
怎么讲
How?
你的整个越狱计划早已酝酿成形
Your whole escape's already wired.
灯一熄  你就越过高墙
Lights out, you're over the wall.
你还要我这样的韩国瘾君子做什么
What do you need a Korean junkie like me for?
你的意思其实是韩国天才吧
Korean genius, you mean.
翻越那堵高墙只是开始
Getting over that wall is just the start.
一旦完成
Once that happens,
就有些只有你能做到的事
there are things only you can do.
回到重点上来  你打了我
Back on point: you hit me.
你要我证明我和你一伙  而不是拉马尔
You wanted proof that I sided with you and not Ramal.
打烂我的嘴唇算什么证明
And splitting my lip does that how?
狗娘养的卡尼尔·乌提斯就是爱演  对不对
Son of a bitch Kaniel Outis keeps playing, doesn't he?
我的手表在哪
Where is my watch?
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你不知道吗
You don't?
等我找到表了
I'm going to break you in half
我要把你劈成两半
when I find that watch, you know?
把这翻个底朝天
Toss the cell.
表不在这
It's not here.
下令整个监狱实行一级防范禁闭
Order a lockdown of the whole prison.
不允许任何人走出牢房一步
No one gets out of their cells
直到找到那块表为止
until that watch is found!
回你牢房里去
一级防范禁闭
进去
我说过  拉马尔哪也去不了
I told you, Ramal's not going anywhere.
只有我们能逃出去
Only we are.
我们会跟其他人一样被锁在自己的囚室里
We're gonna be locked in our box just like the rest of them,
然而只有我们的囚室能逃出去
only our box has a way out.
等两个小时以后  那些灯都灭了
And in two hours when those lights go black,
我们会像幽灵一样从这里消失不见
we're gonna disappear from this place like ghosts.
随便吧
Yeah, all right.
希巴
Sheba!
跟你一伙的都是些什么人
Who are these men you work with?
他们配不上你
They're beneath you.
你才配不上我
You're beneath me.
伤害你我也心痛
It pains me to hurt you,
但良家妇女就得恪守妇道
but a good woman is a humble woman.
给我记住了
Remember that.
那些人是谁
Who are these men?
不重要了
Doesn't matter.
反正他们要离开了
They're leaving.
坏人不是我
I am not the bad guy here.
你我有过一段情
You and I have a history.
上小学时我曾是何等地宠爱你
How I doted on you in grade school,
我又曾是如何等了又等
how I waited and I waited.
你没有等
You did not wait.
你只想强奸我
You tried to rape me!
求你了
Please.
行行好  松开我
Please. Please untie me...
这样我就可以让你再瞎一只眼
...so I can take your other eye.
捷普数码店
营业中
下午好
Afternoon.
我在找我那一部被一个女人偷走的手机
I'm looking for a cell phone that a woman stole from me.
她长这样  对吧
She looks like this?
不  我帮不了你
No, can't help you.
帮不了  还是不愿帮
Can't... or won't?
抱歉  只不过店里有规矩
Sorry. Store policy, that's all.
打烊
捷普数码店
你们要做什么
What are you doing?
我再问一次
‭Let's go again.
你见过她没有
Have you seen her? ‭
见过  见过
Yes. Yes!
她刚来过  大概十分钟前吧
She was here, like, ten minutes ago.
说她手机被黑了  想知道是谁干的
Said her phone was hacked and wanted to know who did it.
她现在知道了  不是吗
And now she knows, doesn't she?
她给我们下了套
She baited us.
是死胡同
Dead end.
波塞冬有没有可能让我们直接杀了她
Any chance Poseidon'll just let us kill her?
将来也许会吧
It might come to that.
等我们出去了  你会去哪里
We get out, where are you going?
回我沙发上
Back to my couch.
我首尔的沙发上
My couch in Seoul,
那里的墙是我的
where the walls are mine,
地板是我的
the floors are mine.
没人能找我麻烦
No one can get to me.
依旧把尘世关在门外  与世隔绝
The world stays outside like it's supposed to.
卡尔加里
Calgary.
加拿大吗
Canada?
我要去当跳台滑雪运动员
I'm going to be a ski jumper.
你从没见过雪  对吧
You've never seen snow, have you?
所以才选那里
That's the point.
我到目前在这个国家所经历的一切
Everything in my life till now in this country--
炎热  仇恨  从不下雪的天
the heat, the hate, the skies that never snow.
你所谈论的那种"尘世"
You talk about the world.
我想在那个世界的另一边[过另一种生活]
I want to be on the other side of it.
纽约州北部
-爸  妈  -儿子
- Hey, Dad. Hey, Mom. - Hi, son.
莎拉  让我来...
Now, Sara, let me, uh...
谢谢
Thanks.
-快请进  -房子真不错
- Come on in. - The house looks great.
稍等一下  不好意思
Oh, give me one sec. Sorry.
喂
Hello?
你好  我是捷普数码店的布莱恩
Hi. This is Brian at Jep's.
我给你激活新手机时记下了你的号码
I got this number when I activated your new phone.
你一直没回来
You never came back.
很抱歉  我想我不会回去了
I'm sorry. I don't think I'm going to.
好吧  我只想告诉你
Well, okay, I just want to let you know
我发现了是谁在黑你的手机
that I figured out who was hacking your phone.
是谁
Who?
是你...  黑了你自己的手机
You... hacked your own phone.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你的拇指指纹就是秘钥  对吧
Your thumbprint is your password, right?
那个黑你手机的人用了你的指纹
Well, whoever hacked your phone used your thumbprint,
所以说  除非你大拇指丢了
so, unless you're missing a thumb,
否则就是你自己
that's you.
我不知道你惹了什么麻烦
I don't know what you're messed up in,
但换做是我  我一定会多加小心了
but I'd watch your back...
你在医院的时候
When you were in the hospital,
袭击我们的女人跟她的同伙又回来了
the woman who attacked us came back with her partner.
什么
What?
他们利用我的手机跟踪了我
They tracked me down using my cell phone,
所以我把手机拿去捷普数码店
so I brought it to Jep's
想找出他们的幕后老板是谁
to try and figure out who they were working for.
等等  莎拉  这事明摆着由警方负责
Wait. Sara, this has police written all over it.
警方至今毫无进展
Police haven't been able to do a thing.
所以呢  你就去了捷普数码店
So, what? You went to Jep's Electronics
试图用反侦察的滥招数搞定吗
in some hackneyed attempt at counter-espionage?
抱歉  抱歉  只是...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It's just...
我明白你有点不知所措
I get you don't know where to turn,
但这也是我的事
but I got a stake in this, too.
好吧  这可事关我的老婆和儿子
‭Okay? This is my wife, my son.
你想报复这帮家伙吗
You want to get back at these guys?
那就去大学
The university.
我是说  那里有资源
I mean, it has real resources,
有计算机科学系
their Computer Sciences Department.
手机的事到此为止  我会把它留在捷普
The phone's done. It's gonna stay at Jep's.
所以你的计划就是  逃避现实吗
So that's your plan-- just bury your head in the sand?
不
No.
不  我这些年学到了
No, I've learned over the years
逃避是最坏的选择  谢谢你了
that's exactly what you don't do. Thank you.
你是哪位
Which one's this?
你在卫生间里搭讪的那位
The one you accosted in a bathroom.
那可不是搭讪  亲爱的
That wasn't accostment, honey.
我搞清楚了一些有关于
I've learned some things
我们两个都在找的那个人的事
about who it is we're apparently both looking for?
但我需要知道你有决心坚持到底
But I need to know that you're willing to go the distance.
我最有决心了  小美人儿
I'm made of the distance, honeysuckle.
我就是决心的化身
I am the distance.
很好
Good.
因为你需要替我去和保罗·凯勒曼聊聊
Because you're gonna have a conversation with Paul Kellerman for me.
不会吧  凯勒曼是幕后主使吗
Bull. Kellerman's behind this?
你得去查清楚这到底是怎么回事
And you are gonna get every shred of information you can
不要放过任何蛛丝马迹
about what's really going on.
十五分钟
15 minutes.
我只是想告诉你  这次是我自己打脸了
I'm soiling myself here, just so you know.
听着  我只说这一件事  好吗
Look, I'm just gonna say one thing, okay?
你就像我的兄弟
You're like a brother to me,
就像一位老大哥一样
like an older brother.
-我不是个好大哥  -确实
- I'm not much of a brother. - ‭Sure.
但重点是之前我一个兄弟都没
Point is that I had zero, nobody,
直到你拉我入伙
till you recruited me.
把我从奥沙克监狱救出来的你
When you pulled me out of that prison in the Ozarks,
作风正派
you had integrity.
当然  当时我知道那是中情局的差事
I know we were doing CIA work, sure,
救他们要的人出去啊什么的
you know, pulling their people out,
但重要的是我们并肩作战
but it was about you and me,
我们把性命都托付给对方
and having each other's back.
之前从哥伦比亚越狱那次也一样
And it didn't matter if you were Ramon Cadena
就算你化名罗曼·卡德纳  我也不在乎
when we did the Colombian break,
还有  阿萨夫...
or, you know Asaf...
他叫什么来着
What was his name?
随便吧  就是埃及那次
Whatever. The one in Egypt.
你还是那个你
You were still you.
这次也一样
And it's the same with this one.
我们让你以卡尼尔·乌提斯的身份
You know, we trump you up as Kaniel Outis,
伪装成国际恐怖分子
big international terrorist.
那只是个名字
It's just a name,
只是张罪行累累的"狼皮"  一个关进监狱的借口
it's just a rap sheet, it's a way to get you locked up.
对吧
Right?
我想问你的是...
I guess what I'm asking you is did...
你被单独监禁时是不是发生了什么事
did something happen to you while you were in solitary?
那时你是否真相信自己是卡尼尔·乌提斯了
Did you become Kaniel Outis in there in your head?
现在你是不是真想把拉马尔救出去
Do you now want Ramal out after all?
我告诉过你了  我们不管拉马尔了
I already told you Ramal is out of the picture.
你是说了  但有件小事...
Yeah, you said that, but one small thing...
计划是我们从上面那个洞口上去
We go up through that hole,
从囚区上面绕着走
and then we skirt above the block.
走到拉马尔囚室正上方  不是吗
Goes right above Ramal's cell, doesn't it?
敲掉几块砖
Knock out a couple tiles,
他就跟我们一起跑了  对吧
he joins the escape, doesn't he?
刚才我们吵完架后  你跟他悄悄说了什么
What did you whisper to him in that moment after the fight?
你跟他说悄悄话了  说了什么
You whispered something, what was it?
九分钟
Nine minutes.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
刚吃晚饭时  他跟我说的
He told me at dinner.
他说他会来救我们
He said he would come for us.
本来只接我一个
It's supposed to be only me,
但我会带上你们
but you will all be coming.
打开五号囚区的门
Open block five.
所有人都出来
Everyone out.
给我彻底搜查
Shakedown.
找到了
Got it.
找到了  穆斯塔法
Found it, Mustapha.
在埃米尔的大衣里
It was in the Emir's coat here.
你相信了那个骗子的鬼话  是吗
You trusted the liar, didn't you?
现在我们只要祈祷灯如约熄灭
Now, we just pray they get the lights out.
萨那
电气工程部
我们得快点了  伙计
We got to hurry, man.
不到十分钟就得断电了
We got less than ten minutes to kill the power.
别担心
Don't worry.
幸运的话  你朋友和我儿子
With luck, both your friend and my son
一小时内就会重获自由了
will be free within the hour.
好的  断路器已关闭
Okay, breakers are down.
现在只要断掉备用电源就行
Now, we just need to pull the redundancies.
就在大厅那头
They're down the hall.
我留下对付保安  快去
I'll stay here and deal with security. Go.
好吧
Okay.
拜托  你在哪啊
Come on, where are you?
不是吧
Come on.
犹豫不决时  就用老办法
When in doubt, go old school.
我们走
Let's go.
启动发电机
Get the generators up.
让囚犯都回牢房
Get these inmates back inside!
快
Now! ‭
我们走  我们走
Let's go, let's go!
把他们的武器抢过来
Get their weapons.
他们想丢下我们自己跑路
They are trying to escape without us.
快去他们的牢房
Get to their cell.
六号囚区  快走
Block six. Come on!
你听到了  兄弟
You heard them, brother.
-六号囚区  -好
- Block six. - ‭Yes.
雅  把你电话给我
Ja, give me your phone.
快
Come on.
配上强光手电
Mount flashlights.
检查每间囚室
Secure every room.
不到万不得已  不要开枪
Shoot only if you have to.
逼不得已时  格杀勿论
And if you do, shoot to kill.
这边
This way.
去六号囚区的近路  兄弟  快
A shortcut to block six, brother, come on!
放开我  你个畜生
Get off me, you sick bastard!
你不挣扎就能少受点罪
It's easier if you don't struggle.
你就这样对我吗
‭This is how you treat me?
准备受死吧  疯狗
You're going to die now, dog.
希巴  希巴  是我  是我
Sheba, Sheba, it's me, it's me.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
林肯  怎么样
Linc, talk to me.
去接头点  汽修店
Get to the rendezvous, the auto shop.
我们赶不到了  希巴伤得很重
We ain't gonna make it. Sheba's busted up real bad.
-怎么回事  -快去接头点
- What happened? - Just get to the rendezvous.
我们得去接应迈克尔  该死的
We got to be there for Michael, damn it!
见鬼  进入一级防范禁闭了
Damn. Lockdown.
屋顶上加派了卫兵
Extra guards on the roof.
问题在于他们会不会离开
Question is whether they move on.
快点  快  快
Quickly! Hurry, hurry!
在这里  这间
It's here, this one!
有麻烦了
We got problems.
-有人要进我们牢房  -有麻烦了
- Guys are trying to get into the cell. - Problem.
-怎么了  -有人来了
- What's wrong? - People coming.
该死的  上面有卫兵
Damn it, we got guards up here.
争取点时间
Try and buy us some time.
交给我
I'm taking care of it.
不好  他们要逃跑了  快
No, they're escaping, hurry!
不  求求你  别丢下我们
No, please! Don't leave us.
求你了  我们是基督徒
Please, we are Christians,
他们会杀了我们的  求你了
they will kill us! Please!
不行  上面还不安全
No, we're still not clear up top.
别让他们上来
Make sure they don't get up.
走
Go!
他们来了  雅
They're coming, Ja.
-怎么样  -不太妙
- How we doing? - Not good.
卫兵靠得更近了
Guards are even closer.
你快上去
Pull yourself up!
帮帮忙  帮帮忙
Help, help!
希德
Sid!
帮帮我
Help me out!
先把他拉上来
Get him up here first.
没门儿
That's not how this works.
你们先把我弟弟拉上去
You pull my brother up first.
快  拉马尔来了
Hurry, Ramal is coming.
搭把手  我发誓我要...
Lend me your hand. I swear I'm gonna...
先把那孩子拉上来
The kid comes up first!
不
No!
退后  退后
Step away, step away.
不  穆萨  穆萨  看着我
No! Muza, Muza, look at me!
穆萨  穆萨
Muza! Muza!
不  不  看着我  兄弟
No! No, look at me, brother.
快走  快走  拉马尔来了
Go, go, go! It's Ramal.
看着我  穆萨
Look at me! Muza!
快  我们最多有一分钟时间逃出去
Hurry. We've got a minute tops to get out of here.
上去  去追他
Get up there, after him.
放下枪
Drop them!
把枪放下
Put it down!
快点
Do it!
不
No!
放下  快
Down, now!
木板横在缺口处  毯子盖住铁丝网
Board spans the gap. Blanket covers the wire.
出来
Get out!
你在这间牢房里干什么
What are you doing in this cell?
他们在房顶上
They're on the roof!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
我信任过你  卡尼尔·乌提斯
I trusted you, Kaniel Outis.
你却骗了我
And you lied to me.
我以真主和"哈里发"王国军队的名义[伊斯兰教王权或辖地]
By God and my armies of the caliphate,
要你以死谢罪
you will die for it.
或许就在明天
Maybe even tomorrow.
莎拉
Sara...
我说这些话会让你身陷险境
I'm putting you in danger by saying this,
但可能也没关系  因为我到时已死
but maybe it doesn't matter because I'll be dead,
那么他们就会放过你
and they'll leave you alone.
但我爱你
But I love you.
要知道  当年我爱着你
You see, I loved you.
也从未停止过爱你
I never stopped loving you.
这整个骗局  都是为了你
This whole lie, it was for you.
莎拉  如果我真的死了
Sara, if I... if I do die,
别让他们在墓碑上刻卡尼尔·乌提斯
don't let them put Kaniel Outis on the headstone
因为那从来不是真正的我
because that's never who I was.
让他们刻上我的真名
Make them put my real name,
那个始终如一的我
the man I have always been.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
越 狱 第五季第三集
第五季第三集